[Music]
you
hello and happy ongoing feast of Easter
today is the sixth Sunday of Easter my
name is Troy Wojtek and I'm the director
of ministry here at the Catholic Student
Center additionally I serve the graduate
students on the Danforth campus thank
you for joining us online for our
virtual mass it is a joy to serve you in
this way to be able to bring mass to
your residential home from your
spiritual home we encourage you to
create a sacred space for yourself as
you view and participate in this virtual
mass light a candle put across or an
icon on the table in front of you turn
off other devices and we encourage you
to do the typical movements and postures
formats standing kneeling for more tips
about this check out our YouTube channel
in the video about creating a sacred
space at home we will continue to post
the thought of the day from our campus
ministry team once a week after this
week throughout the summer it will be
called Wednesday wisdom and it will be
on our youtube channel check out our
website for the link to that also
continue to submit your petitions via
our website or the link in our Numan
notes we will continue to hold them up
during Mass and throughout the week as
you may have heard the Archdiocese of
st. Louis will be allowing public masses
to resume starting May 18th the
dispensation for the Sunday obligation
however will still be in place because
many parishes will still not be able to
offer mass given the risks and safety of
the faithful
additionally archbishop carlson has left
the decision up to each community to
decide what is best for them the CSC
will not be offering public mass at this
time because almost all our students are
gone and we do not want to endanger the
safety of anyone we will keep you posted
on when we will begin to make public
Mass available to all our students we
miss you and even though we know your
summer break has begun please do not
hesitate to reach out to us if you need
anything and keep an eye out for some of
our virtual programs that we will be
hosting throughout the summer
and finally to the class of 2020
congratulations on being finished we are
dedicating today's mass to you in honor
of this week being the original week for
commencement we know that some
individual programs are still hosting
virtual ceremonies this week and so we
are keeping you in prayers throughout
the whole week
additionally we plan to celebrate you in
a more formal way in the future that
will correspond both wash use plans for
commencement and celebration of the
class of 2020 again thank you for
joining us and God bless
[Music]
[Applause]
this is the day the Lord has made me
glad in the name of the Father the Son
and the Holy Spirit amen the Grace and
the peace and the joy of the risen
Christ be with you all thank you the
gospel question in this Easter season
this Sunday is how good are you at
asking for help
Lord Jesus you were sent to save us you
were sent to set us free
you were sent so that we might live a
whole new level of life but there are so
many ways we didn't let you do that for
us and so we say lord have mercy we say
Christ have mercy we say lord have mercy
may Almighty God have mercy on us
forgive us our sin bring us to
everlasting life
[Music]
[Applause]
Grint
Almighty God that we may celebrate with
heartfelt devotion these days of joy
which we keep in honor of the risen Lord
and that what we realize in remembrance
we may always hold to in what we do
through our Lord Jesus Christ your son
who lives and reigns with you in the
unity of the Holy Spirit one God for
ever and ever
a reading from the Acts of the Apostles
Philip went down to the city of Samaria
and proclaimed the Christ to them with
one Accord the crowds paid attention to
what was said by Philip when they heard
it and saw the signs he was doing for
unclean spirits crying out in a loud
voice came out of many possessed people
and many paralyzed or crippled people
were cured there was great joy in that
city
now when the Apostles in Jerusalem heard
that Samaria had accepted the Word of
God they sent them Peter and John who
went down and prayed for them that they
might receive the Holy Spirit for had
not yet fallen upon any of them they had
only been baptized in the name of the
Lord Jesus then they laid hands on them
and they received the Holy Spirit the
word of the Lord
[Music]
well
[Applause]
[Music]
a reading from the first letter of Peter
beloved sanctify Christ as Lord in your
hearts always be ready to give an
explanation to anyone who asks you for a
reason for your hope
but do with gentleness and reverence
keeping your conscience clear so that
when your maligned those who defame your
good conduct in Christ may themselves be
put to shame for it is better to suffer
for doing good if that be the will of
God than for doing evil for Christ also
suffered for sins once the righteous for
the sake of the unrighteous he might
lead you to God put to death in the
flesh he was brought to life in the
spirit the word of the Lord
[Music]
[Applause]
the Lord be with you
a reading from the holy Gospel according
to John
[Music]
Jesus said to his disciples if you love
me you will keep my Commandments and I
will ask the Father and He will give you
another advocate to be with you always
the Spirit of Truth whom the world
cannot accept because it neither sees
nor knows him but you know him because
he remains with you and will be in you I
will not leave you orphans I will come
to you in a little while the world will
no longer see me but you will see me
because I live and you will live on that
day you will realize that I am in the
father and you are in me and I in you
whoever has my Commandments and observes
them is the one who loves me and whoever
loves me will be loved by my father and
I will love him and reveal myself to him
the gospel of the Lord
I was at dinner the other night and the
husband and dad of this little family of
now young adults was telling me a story
he had heard recently of a scientist who
had run 2,000 obituaries through some
sort of program that picks up on the
most commonly used words in obituaries
and what he came up with after running
2,000 obituaries through that program
what he came up with in the obituaries
of the famous and the not so famous are
two words two words jumped out at them
one was John so if your parents name
you're dying you're doing pretty good
unless you're a girl second the second
word that jumped out at them
was the word help that's right help
they helped people driving home I
couldn't stop thinking really about that
little story he told that he had shared
with the rest of us and isn't that just
the truth people who help us who really
help us are dear to us quite often maybe
even strangers sometimes what those
obituaries tell us is that what we
remember about a person is that in one
way or another they helped us they
helped to succeed they helped us through
difficult times
they helped us finish what we started
they helped us create something new or
resolve something old they helped us get
back on track they had some sort of
impact on the world
they helped us dream
they helped us accomplish our dreams
they helped us get back up when we were
knocked down
they helped us back to faith they helped
us get back to hope again in little ways
and in big ways they helped us what I
hear commented on again and again is
those frontline workers that we talk
about so often and we thank so profusely
and rightly so they're helping us in a
way we really need to be helped right
now and even though scientists isolated
in those labs trying to come up with
some way of repairing the damage of this
virus even though scientists are helping
us they're having an impact on society
what this rather abstract gospel is all
about is to tell us that in the triune
mystery we call God there is that in God
in the mystery that is always always
always helping us wanting to help us
that is always helping us helping us
from the inside out and from the outside
in God helps us God is in our life to
help us and that in the triune mystery
that does just that is the one Jesus
called our advocate our helper really
the Holy Spirit the Holy Spirit is that
in the China and mystery that is always
in us for us through us trying to help
us are you hearing this my
friends we tend to think of how we can
serve God but can we let God serve us
can we let God help us when we need it
or is God the afterthought because we're
too busy trying to fix everything
ourselves
even so if we begin to know a God who is
ready and willing to help at all times
any time in the middle of the day at
night or the bright of day if we begin
to believe in and trust in a God who
once and is willing and can help us even
so we will begin to see that we really
can and rightly so help others no wonder
it feels so good to help people
it's because we are in the image and
likeness of the one who is a helper to
all we are compelled to help because the
God in us is the helper you see it's who
we are it's it's who we are to help
people it's in our DNA in our divine DNA
to help others that's why it feels so
good to do it so many are hesitant to
ask for help
we don't feel worthy of people's time
and attention we don't want to put
anybody out we don't want to be a burden
on somebody we're too proud to admit we
need help we want to maintain control so
we don't ask for help but in the process
in the process of not being willing to
ask for help we deny others the chance
to be doing what God does all the time
what God wants to do which is to help us
we're denying them that privilege I read
the other day that calls to the suicide
hotline in this country during this
pandemic have gone up 1,000% that might
be a troubling statistic to many but I'm
seeing all these people willing to ask
for help and that's not a small thing my
friends that's a miracle in itself that
people know that they're in trouble and
that they can ask for help before it's
too late
in these pandemic days there are a lot
of people who need somebody who needs
somebody to help even if it's just our
company maybe to hang with them a bit
online or at a safe physical distance
away back in the old days when I as a
kid my parents would could make my day
when I'd say to them what are we doing
this weekend always afraid of boredom
and they would say we're having company
companies coming over Gary and they
would see me light up like a firecracker
that meant somebody was coming over and
to me that was so exciting company is
such a good way to help people
we need good company you and I and we
can be good company to others these days
what a wonderful way to help somebody
called me just a couple days ago and he
said he and his wife were not rolling in
cash by any means but we know there's a
lot of people worse off than we are and
so
do you have any thoughts about where we
can make a donation just to help a
little bit that's what I'm talking about
no wonder it touches us no wonder it
touches us even to the point of Tears to
see and witness people helping people
and there ain't no pandemic in the world
that can keep us from doing that let me
say it again
there ain't no pandemic in the world
that keep them keep us even though we're
sheltering in place no physical just to
all physical distancing that we can that
can keep us from helping people that's
the truth and this thing about wearing a
mask holy cow let's up make this a red
thing or a blue thing let's I make this
about civil liberties are my rights the
only question that matters with this
issue are any issue in our lives is this
question is this going to help somebody
is this going to help anybody and if the
answer is yes hello that's all the
matters period and the sentence is this
going to help somebody anybody
that's the only question that ever
matters is it going to help anybody
because with this gospel with this
gospel makes clear is that if this helps
anybody it's gonna help me it's gonna
help me to be able to help so many have
helped me personally through these eight
weeks of sheltering in place so many
have helped me in little ways by letting
me borrow even a hair trimmer to cut my
unkempt hair to the other day someone
brought me a frozen ice cream chocolate
covered fruit topped ice cream pie
woohoo
the only thing missing was a donut on
top but this is happening all the time I
came home last night maybe at 11:00
after a long walk in the evening and
right there on a table just outside the
doors of her chapel outside someone
delivered food and said it there for me
for when I got back I don't know about
on the coasts because it always seems
like sometimes we think differently from
the coast to here in the Midwest
perhaps there they think of therapy is
almost a badge of honor and so people
talk about going to see their therapist
so freely I've always noticed coming
from st. Louis in the Midwest here it
was perceived for a long time as kind of
a stigma to go to therapy we should be
able to pull ourselves up by our
bootstraps you know
wrong again banana breath sure that
might be humbling to ask for help but
that's the right kind of humbling
that's the humbling of Christ
that's the humility that opens for us
who are willing to ask for
the gates of heaven today and at the
hour of our death
in these pandemic days more of us need
to have that humility to ask for help
starting with God
starting with God we can ask God for
help when we hit those troubled times
when I'm in troubled and I don't know
where to go we just sang all we have to
do is kneel down next to our bad there's
only one word we have to pray help
and remember that in the asking we are
opening up the possibility of a great
grace and a great gift even to another
human being when they when we ask them
for help this week I had to ask for help
about a small thing maybe a small thing
to me it was a little bit bigger I had
to ask a friend for a favor and yes
honestly frankly it's always a little
embarrassing to me even from a friend
can I tell you her response she texted
back of course we love you thanks for
asking it means the world to us that you
did it fills our hearts to fill your
need
followed by triple hearts and five
exclamation points there you have it is
a grace to ask for help and it is a
great grace to be able to help and I
might add a privilege
to remember the old song many of us grew
up with it was from the Beatles and it
was called help it's kind of a fun song
and so in the light of this gospel about
this God who wants to help us all the
time wherever you are whatever you do
and if you're alone in your house you'll
probably got it the easiest because you
won't mind sounding and looking like a
fool but if you're with somebody else
have them join in especially your little
kids and if you're with college students
good luck
[Music]
[Applause]
help me get my face back
[Music]
[Applause]
feedback
[Music]
our response to God's Word is to profess
our faith our trust in God in the
ancient words of the Apostles Creed I
believe that God the Father Almighty
Creator of heaven and earth and in Jesus
Christ His only Son our Lord who was
conceived by the Holy Spirit born of the
Virgin Mary suffered under Pontius
Pilate was crucified died and was buried
he descended into hell on the third day
he rose again from the dead he ascended
into heaven and is seated at the right
hand of God the Father Almighty from
there he will come to judge the living
and the dead
I believe in the Holy Spirit the Holy
Catholic Church the communion of saints
the forgiveness of sins the resurrection
of the body and life everlasting amen
sanding on the ground of our faith that
God wants to help us let us put our cry
for help into words right now
let us pray that we as individuals and
the church universal remember that when
we are in need to ask God for help first
and trust that extra help and strength
is available to us we pray to the Lord
Lord in our prayer
let us pray that we be open to
opportunities to help others and that we
may be given the courage to seek out
opportunities to help others may we
experience the joy that comes from
serving our neighbor we pray to the Lord
Lord hear our prayer let us pray for all
the students of the class of 2020 as
they complete their time at Wash U and
st. Louis College of Pharmacy despite
the way this semester has ended may
their time as students become a
launching pad into helping make this
world a better place we pray to the Lord
Lord hear our prayer for all those who
are sick or who have died from the
coronavirus or from any other cause and
for all those who lend help to the sick
despite the risk to their own health may
we as the body of Christ show compassion
and comfort to the suffering as best we
can we pray to the Lord
Lord hear our prayer now let us pause
for all the petitions that have been
submitted by our community and for those
you hold dear in your hearts right now
as you join us at home
we pray to the Lord Lord hear our prayer
and so God there's only one word we need
to say right now one word that carries
all of this to you help we pray this
through Christ the Lord
[Music]
we pause now to encourage you to bring
your own offering to the table through
our electronic giving and prayers for
our community
joining your sacrifice to the sacrifice
of this mess thank you for your more
generosity
[Music]
our Easter table is prepared the table
around which we gather to ask for God's
help pray my friends that my sacrifice
and yours be acceptable to God our
Father may our prayers rise up to you O
Lord together with the sacrificial
offerings so that your purified by your
graciousness
we may be conformed to the mysteries of
your love through Christ our Lord amen
my friends the Lord be with you
lift up your hearts let ask you thanks
to the Lord our God it is truly right
and just our duty and our salvation at
all times to acclaim you O Lord but in
this time above all to laud you yet more
gloriously when Christ our Passover has
been sacrificed for with the old order
destroyed a universe cast down is
renewed an integrity of life is restored
to us in Christ there for filled with
Paschal joy every land every people
exalts in your praise and even the
powers of heaven sing together the
unending hymn of your glory as they
acclaim
[Music]
you are indeed holy O Lord and all you
have created rightly gives you praise
for through your son our Lord Jesus
Christ by the power and working of your
Holy Spirit you give life to all things
and make them holy and you never cease
to gather a people to yourself so that
from the rising of the Sun to its
setting a pure sacrifice may be offered
to your name therefore O Lord we humbly
implore you by the same spirit
graciously make holy these gifts we
brought to you for consecration that
they may become the body and blood of
your son our Lord Jesus Christ at whose
command we celebrate these mysteries for
on the night he was betrayed he took
bread and giving you thanks he said the
blessing he broke the bread he gave it
to his disciples saying take this all of
you and eat of it for this is my body
which will be given up for you
in a similar way when supper was ended
Jesus took the chalice filled with wine
and giving you thanks he said the
blessing and gave the chalice to his
disciples saying take this all of you
drink from it for this is the chalice of
My Blood the blood of the new and
eternal covenant it will be poured out
for you and for many for the forgiveness
of sins do this in memory of me
the mystery of Fame
[Music]
[Applause]
therefore Lord as we celebrate the
memorial of the saving passion of your
son his wondrous resurrection and
ascension into heaven and as we look
forward to his coming in glory we offer
you in Thanksgiving this holy and living
sacrifice look we pray upon the oblation
of your church and recognizing the
sacral vicious a CRO fishel victim by
whose death you reconciled us to
yourself grant that we who are nourished
by the body and blood of your son and
filled with His Holy Spirit that we may
become one body one spirit in Christ may
make of us an eternal offering to you so
they may come to know the inheritance of
your elect especially with Mary the
Mother of God Joseph your blessed
apostles and glorious martyrs and all
the Saints on whose constant
intercession in your presence we rely
for unfailing help may this sacrifice of
our reconciliation we pray Lord advance
the peace and salvation of all the world
be pleased to confirm in faith and
charity your pilgrim church on earth
your servant Francis our Pope Robert our
Bishop the order of Bishops all the
clergy and the entire people you have
gained for your own
listen graciously to the prayers of this
family you've gathered here before you
in your compassion merciful Father
gather to yourself all your children
gathered throughout the world and to our
departed brothers and sisters and to all
who are pleasing to you at their passing
from this life give kind admittance to
your kingdom there we hope to enjoy
forever the fullness of your glory
through Christ our Lord through whom you
bestow on the world everything that is
good
through him and with him and in him O
God Almighty father in the unity of the
Holy Spirit all glory and honor is yours
for ever and ever
[Music]
[Applause]
when they asked Jesus to teach them how
to pray as he prayed it's really obvious
that he wanted to teach them to ask for
help
to call God by God's own name and also
they asked for our daily bread the bread
we need to live food and love and so as
our Savior has commanded we say our
Father who art in heaven hallowed be thy
name thy kingdom come thy will be done
on earth as it is in heaven give us this
day our daily bread and forgive us our
trespasses as we forgive those who
trespass against us and lead us not into
temptation but deliver us from evil
deliver us Lord from every evil grant us
your peace in our day in your mercy keep
us free from sin and protect us from all
distress as we await the Blessed hope
and the coming of our Savior Jesus
Christ for the kingdom the power and the
glory are yours now and forever Lord
Jesus Christ who said to your apostles
peace I leave you my peace I give you
look not on our sins but on the faith of
your church and graciously grant her
peace and unity in accordance with your
will who live and reign for ever and
ever
my friends the peace and the joy of the
risen Christ be with each of you always
[Music]
[Applause]
behold the lamb of God behold him who
takes away the sins of the world blessed
are those called to the supper of the
Lamb
lord I am not worthy that you should
enter under my roof but only say the
word and my soul shall be healed
my Jesus I believe that you are present
in the Most Holy Sacrament I love you
above all things and I desire to receive
you into my soul the body of Christ
since I cannot at this moment we see you
sacramentally come spiritually into my
heart I embrace you as if you were
already there in you nightly cell holy
to you never permit me to be separated
from you
[Music]
[Applause]
J
[Music]
in these few minutes after communion the
time of gratitude traditionally worn by
the presence of Christ spiritually are
physically in our hearts right now and
this spirit this advocate this helper
the God who helps with us very much with
us let's find it in our hearts to be
grateful and even to mention quietly
people who have helped us people have
been there for us for us here at the CSC
it's so many students so many students
who help us more than they know and who
have given us the great gift of letting
us help them and all the donors
especially this past Easter the
collection that broke all records here
in the midst of a pandemic where we
matched the challenge of a family who
very much believes in us
and what about you in your life who is
it that makes you that frozen vanilla
ice cream chocolate covered fruit topped
dessert all the way to listen unto your
broken heart just be with us right now
in gratitude for those who have helped
us and the chance many have given us to
help them
[Music]
almighty and ever living God who
restored us to eternal life and the
resurrection of Christ increase in us we
pray the fruits of this Paschal
sacrament and pour into our hearts the
strength of this saving food through
Christ our Lord and thank you for
joining us today the Lord be with you
and with your spirit may Almighty God
bless you the Father the Son and the
Holy Spirit amen this mass has ended let
us go in the joy of the risen Christ
[Music]
[Applause]
Oh
[Music]
[Applause]
what
[Music]
[Applause]
baseball's gracious
[Music]
[Applause]
you